Alissa Troiano

Full Stack Software Developer

alissatroiano@alissatroiano.com | 914-562-0119 | github.com/alissatroiano | linkedin.com/in/alissatroiano/

Executive Summary

A results-driven Full Stack Software Developer with experience participating in the full software development life-cycle, from planning to deployment. Willing to learn new technologies, work long hours and do whatever it takes to succeed. To see my projects and repositories, please review my GitHub (https://github.com/alissatroiano)

Technical Skill Set

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 Frameworks: Django, Flask, React, MVC, Bootstrap, jQuery

Education and Training

Education:

2019-2020 Code Institute - Diploma in Software Development

2009 - 2012 Fashion Institute of Technology - BS, Advertising Marketing & Communications

Technical Courses:

2020 SoloLearn JavaScript Fundamentals
2018-2019 Codecademy Frontend Engineer Skill Path

Honors and Awards

07/16/2022 | 1st Place | Code Institute Emoji Day Hackathon | Emojourney | Travel Guide (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript) 06/20/2022 | 1st Place | Code Institute Pride Hackathon | Inklusion | LGBTQIA+ Art Gallery (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript)

04/22/2022 | 1st Place | Code Institute Earth Day Hackathon | <u>Electrillo</u> | EV/Fuel Savings Tool (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ISON)

02/28/2022 | 1st Place | Code Institute Valentine's Day Hackathon | <u>Smitten</u> | Word game (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSON) **11/28/2020** | Merit Award for Code Institute Milestone 2 Project | <u>Game of Facts</u> | Trivia game (JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS)

07/10/2020 | Distinction Award for Code Institute Milestone 1 Project | <u>Infinity</u> | Frontend website (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap)

Professional Experience

Nanny 2019 – Present

Pelham, New York

It is my responsibility to oversee daily after-school pickup, homework help, pet care, and other activities for this family as needed. I started this position because I needed to work while pursuing my education in software development, and I continue to demonstrate strong organizational skills in this role.

- Entrusted with daily after-school pickup Monday-Friday
- Exercise patience to dictate homework and studying

Use creativity to incorporate education and analytical thinking activities into playtime

Freelance Graphic Designer

2018 - 2019

I created custom designs for digital & print clients during this time period. I used Etsy and word of mouth to communicate with clients before building my own custom domain. It was my responsibility to follow up with customers, stay on top of schedule and produce creative content.

- Used graphic design skills to create custom t-shirts and apparel
- Managed inventory, sales and customer requests in online Etsy shop
- Designed custom print graphics for weddings

Lesser Evil Healthy Snacks; Danbury, CT Territory Sales Manager

2016 - 2017

It was my responsibility to visit stores in the northeast territory to pitch products, network with and assist store managers in ordering products.

My efforts increased sales and led to the product's placement in new stores. I accomplished this by meeting and following up with store buyers, performing in-store tasting events for customers, and analyzing sales data to make informed decisions.

- Traveled assigned territory to pitch products and network with grocery buyers
- Conducted product tasting events for customers
- Analyzed sales data and behavior to guide decisions

Hobbies & Interests

Code Institute Hackathons

12/2021 - Present

I competed with my team to build a frontend application that met the challenge criteria. I contributed to my team's progress by tackling extra tasks to complete the project before the deadline. I used interpersonal skills and technical knowledge to speak for the team and present our project to judges & participants.

- Worked with a remote team to complete time sensitive, competitive coding challenges
- Volunteered time and technical skills to carry out extra programming tasks
- Represented team while presenting final project to assessors

GitHub Copilot Technical Preview Community

2021 - 2022

It is my responsibility to monitor the GitHub Copilot AI extension during local development. To help the development team improve the product, I document and report bugs to GitHub's private technical preview repository and engage in

- Observe AI behavior in local IDE, focusing on prediction patterns
- Document findings with as much detail as possible
- Report observations and bugs to community

References are available upon request.